<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intro Pack on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/intro-pack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intro Pack on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/intro-pack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Package</title>
      <link>/posts/intropackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intropackage/</guid>
      <description>Expense report and Vacation Primula [TODO] Procedure of filing expense report (including LRS)
How to select meal benefits  For each meal M on each day there are three options:  Checking box with meal benefits (B): choose this option if meal M is included as part of another fee (for example, a lunch that is included in a conference registration fee) and M is not a breakfast. Checking box without meal benefits (N): choose this optin if meal M is offered by a third party (for example, if you are a guest and your host pays for M) or M is a breakfast (which is usually included in hotel fee) Not checking either box (E): choose this option if you pay for meal M yourself (for example, you go out to a restaurant and pay your share of the bill out of your own pocket) (Don&amp;rsquo;t clicking on anything)   The consequences of these options are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>Some useful links Handbook for doctoral studies Procedure for licentiate Thesis, followup meetings and needed forms
Doctoral Portal
Insidan
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)
Licentiate degree
Follow-up meetings
GTS courses</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student_union/</guid>
      <description>Student union As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right (and the obligation) to be part of the Student Union. Sign up to the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecent. The fee is 250 SEK fee every semester.
** Student union card is REQUIRED for taking an exam ** NOTE: If you are a Chalmers PhD student, in order to graduate you need to prove you have payed the fee to the Student Union for all the semesters you have work at Chalmers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>