<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intro Pack on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/intro-pack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intro Pack on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2017 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/intro-pack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/posts/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/internet/</guid>
      <description>Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go toCDKS
Home directory of remote servers You have a limited (but large) space at Chalmers servers just for you! - enter in your Termial - type &amp;lsquo;ssh -X CID@remote12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Package</title>
      <link>/posts/intropackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intropackage/</guid>
      <description>Expense report and Vacation Primula [TODO] Procedure of filing expense report (including LRS)
How to select meal benefits  For each meal M on each day there are three options:  Checking box with meal benefits (B): choose this option if meal M is included as part of another fee (for example, a lunch that is included in a conference registration fee) and M is not a breakfast. Checking box without meal benefits (N): choose this optin if meal M is offered by a third party (for example, if you are a guest and your host pays for M) or M is a breakfast (which is usually included in hotel fee) Not checking either box (E): choose this option if you pay for meal M yourself (for example, you go out to a restaurant and pay your share of the bill out of your own pocket) (Don&amp;rsquo;t clicking on anything)   The consequences of these options are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>/posts/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/library/</guid>
      <description>Access material when you off-campus Add your publications to CLP Books You can request and access material such as books and articles you need for you research at the Library website You can request/recommand a (paper/online) book for library. (the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary need to be relavant to your research area).
Lending times:
Books : 1-3 weeks
E-book, articles: 1-3 days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses You report vacation application, leave, expenses compensations in
Primula
login: CID
password: CID password
Here you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep you Persona Data page up-to-date (in particular when you move)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing / Printers</title>
      <link>/posts/print/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/print/</guid>
      <description>Printer Web interface to printers You can use web interface to see nearby printers, download drivers or directly send pdf, txt files to be printed.
Ubuntu installation (tested on 14.x, 12.x) Download Drivers
 in &amp;ldquo;system-config-printer&amp;rdquo; type smb://print.chalmers.se/cse-ed-5473-laser1 (or your printer address) add corresponding driver file (*.PDD). It fails to authenticate first, but you can set the password here when you look at printer queue. username: NET/CID  Printing via ipp/kerberos: Copy krb5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software/</guid>
      <description>Free commercial softwares Worth looking (OS and utitily software(antivirus) and domain specific softwares like MATLAB and &amp;hellip;) Windows share:
 smb://syros.ce.chalmers.se \\syros.ce.chalmers.se
 Domain: NET
 username: CID
  syros directory tree output of &amp;ldquo;tree -L 3 -d&amp;rdquo; on smb://syros.ce.chalmers.se/program/
Microsoft tools Different version of Windows (even ancient DOS), SQL server and visual studio and more. You need to specify your university (Chalmers).
Microsoft tools Almost everything except MS-Office which is accessable from SYROS server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student_union/</guid>
      <description>Student union As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right (and the obligation) to be part of the Student Union. Sign up to the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecent. The fee is 250 SEK fee every semester.
** Student union card is REQUIRED for taking an exam ** NOTE: If you are a Chalmers PhD student, in order to graduate you need to prove you have payed the fee to the Student Union for all the semesters you have work at Chalmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links (GENERAL)</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>PhD useful links (general) Handbook for doctoral studies Procedure for licentiate Thesis, followup meetings and needed forms
Doctoralportal
Insidan
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)
Licentiate degree
Follow-up meetings</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useful links (general)</title>
      <link>/posts/middlepack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 14:17:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/middlepack/</guid>
      <description>PhD useful links (general) Handbook for doctoral studies Procedure for licentiate Thesis, followup meetings and needed forms
Doctoralportal
Insidan
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)
Licentiate degree
Follow-up meetings
Travel Approval Before you go: Find out cost estimate, check with your supervisor if your project can cover the cost. Fill in the new e-form (the form will be sent to your line manager for signature and to your division secretary for reference).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>