<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get Involved on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/get-involved/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get Involved on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/get-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman</title>
      <link>/posts/ombudsman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ombudsman/</guid>
      <description>CSE PhD Ombudsman: Matthías Páll Gissurarson (pallm [at] chalmers [dot] se) Matthías was elected in during May of 2020.
Here you can find the official statute for the CSE PhD Ombudsman.
This is your chance to improve you fellow PhD student&amp;rsquo;s experience, by listening them and helping them to look at their problem from a different prospective. Despite there are several different contacts that are there to help you, such as the Doktorandombudet (DOMB), in agreement with the CSE Research School, we re-introduce the figure of the CSE PhD Ombudsman as an elected PhD student that has the role to locally listen and help other PhD students by giving an objective point of view on difficult and sometimes tedious PhD related problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buddy System</title>
      <link>/posts/buddysystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/buddysystem/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking to expand our buddy pool with buddies from all divisions! This is your chance to improve a new PhD student’s experience, by helping them figure out everything you wish you had known when you started here!
Do you have some wise advice or useful tips you wish someone had given you at the start of your PhD journey?
This could be anything from questions about navigating department bureaucracy, advice on apartment hunting in Gothenburg, tips on socializing in a new city/country, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>