<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman</title>
      <link>/posts/ombudsman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ombudsman/</guid>
      <description>CSE PhD Ombudsman: Matthías Páll Gissurarson (pallm [at] chalmers [dot] se) Matthías was elected in during May of 2020.
About the Ombudsman Role Here you can find the official statute for the CSE PhD Ombudsman.
Despite there being several different contacts that are there to help you, such as the Doktorandombud (DOMB), in agreement with the CSE Research School we re-introduce the position of the CSE PhD Ombudsman as an elected PhD student that has the local role to listen and help other PhD students by giving an objective point of view on difficult, or sometimes tedious, PhD related problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buddy System</title>
      <link>/posts/buddysystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/buddysystem/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking to expand our buddy pool with buddies from all divisions! This is your chance to improve a new PhD student’s experience, by helping them figure out everything you wish you had known when you started here!
Do you have some wise advice or useful tips you wish someone had given you at the start of your PhD journey?
This could be anything from questions about navigating department bureaucracy, advice on apartment hunting in Gothenburg, tips on socializing in a new city/country, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is the council?</title>
      <link>/posts/council-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-who/</guid>
      <description> Linda Erlenhov
    Irene Lobo Valbuena
    Roc R. Currius
    Mazen Mohammad
    Ziming Wang
    Emil Carlsson
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD student Ombudsman Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD student Ombudsman (hereafter referred to as “the PhD ombudsman”) is an official role held by a PhD student, nominated and elected by the doctoral students at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and approved by the CSE department and/or the graduate school.
 The role of the PhD ombudsman is to help PhD students who experience difficulties during the course of their PhD, by providing counsel and acting as a neutral intermediary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity Plan</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</guid>
      <description>This activity plan outlines the items and issues which the council plans to work on during its term in 2019-2020. This is a high-level, strategic plan of activities.
PhD students Representation Background Representation of PhD students in various department committees, such as the department council or research education committee such as DS, SWEET, PhD Mingle, etc.
Action We plan to properly represent the PhD students in these different committees and report back the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps</title>
      <link>/posts/first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-steps/</guid>
      <description>The first days when you start your PhD in an unknown place can be a bit disorienting or overwhelming, so here is a (possibly incomplete) checklist of things you should keep in mind for your first days around. (If you find out there&amp;rsquo;s information that should be included or updated, please send us a mail!)
Also, we very much recommend, specially if you are coming from another country, that you also read the PhD Student Guide made by DS to get an idea of all the things you might need before you start working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organisational Structure</title>
      <link>/posts/organisational-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/organisational-structure/</guid>
      <description>These are the people that are in charge of you, in one way or another. You should find out who each one of them is.
 Supervisor: (possibly together with a co-supervisor) is the person who will overview your research, and who you should go to for any research-related issues. Examiner: Is the person who will act as your examiner during your PhD; they evaluate your progress and decide if a course you want to attend will count towards your PhD credits, so ask them about that before choosing to join a course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD Student Council Last update: 2018-05-09
Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council (hereafter referred to as “the council”) is a group of representatives for the doctoral students at the combined Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) at Chalmers University of Technology and Gothenburg University (hereafter referred to as “the department”). The name of the council is “The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Documents</title>
      <link>/posts/council-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-documents/</guid>
      <description>Council StatutesActivity PlanOmbudsman Statutes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-Up Meetings</title>
      <link>/posts/follow-up-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/follow-up-meetings/</guid>
      <description>What are Follow-up Meetings? TODO
Scheduling You should have at least one follow-up meeting every year, the first one being about 6 months after you start working at Chalmers. If things happen that might prevent you from following the plan set in your most recent follow-up meeting, such as sick leave or parental leave, you should schedule a new meeting as soon as possible to discuss what changes are needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTS - Generic &amp; Transferable Skills</title>
      <link>/posts/gts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gts/</guid>
      <description>During your education you need to obtain several credits from GTS courses, some of which are mandatory.
List of GTS courses https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/working-at-chalmers/employee/role-related-development/development-for-phd-students/
List of mandatory and optional courses for Chalmers students https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/courses/courses-and-activities-within-gts/
List of mandatory courses for GU students https://medarbetarportalen.gu.se/internt-itufak/utbildning-pa-forskarniva/kurser/?languageId=100001&amp;amp;skipSSOCheck=true
More information on GTS courses gathered by the Doctoral Students Guild at Chalmers: https://www.notion.so/Generic-and-Transferable-Skills-GTS-a554319dc8554789b284e3339a688bd1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Licentiate Degree</title>
      <link>/posts/licenciate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/licenciate/</guid>
      <description>About halfway through your PhD studies at Chalmers you are required to defend your Licentiate thesis. This is a formal presentation with your examiner and an external opponent, where you should present the work you have done up to that moment.
The following document has information on how to prepare for the seminar. Note there&amp;rsquo;s specific guidelines for CSE, make sure to adhere to those too: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/licentiate/preparations-for-licentiate-seminars/
If you are a Chalmers student, to be eligible for the Licentiate degree you are required to have completed a series of credits, some of which need to be from specific GTS courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis LaTeX Template</title>
      <link>/posts/thesis-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thesis-template/</guid>
      <description>We at the council have a github repository with a LaTeX template for you to use for your Licentiate or PhD thesis.
You should double-check the requirements for your thesis and that the template matches them.
If the requirements have been updated, we would appreciate very much if you could send a pull-request to fix the template.
We will welcome any other improvements that you find it needs as pull-requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>Some useful links Unofficial PhD Student Guide by DS
Roles and Responsabilities
Intranet Here you might be able to find most of the information you might need about anything in the PhD. The drawbacks are there&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of information that might not be relevant to you so things are sometimes difficult to find. Requires login.
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Trips</title>
      <link>/posts/travelex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/travelex/</guid>
      <description>Chalmer&amp;rsquo;s Guidelines In the following link you can find the official guide from chalmers to book a trip: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/book-a-trip/
This link gives the basic guidelines for what expenses are covered and how you should pay for them and register them: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/expenses-travel-bill-and-entertainment/
Travel Approval Before you go: Find out cost estimate, check with your supervisor if your project can cover the cost. Fill in a BTA form (This form might be outdated, ask your division secretary just in case) (the form will be sent to your division head for signature and to your division secretary for reference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses Chalmers employees use the Primula portal to apply for vacation days and leave, report sick days, and apply to be compensated for travel expenses and other expenses.
You log in with your CID username and password.
There you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep your Personal Data page up-to-date (in particular if you move to a new address).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software &amp; Hardware</title>
      <link>/posts/software-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Internet Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go to CDKS
Email IMAP  imap.chalmers.se - port: 993 username : CID Auth method: CID password Connection: SSL/TLS // Note : Thunderbird test doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits (Discounts)</title>
      <link>/posts/benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benefits/</guid>
      <description>Health expense refund As a Chalmers employee you have the right to be refunded for up to 2000SEK/year for expenses related to health and wellness.
Find more information at the intranet https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/working-at-chalmers/working-environment-health/health/wellness/
Mecenat The Mecenat card from DS gives you access to more student discounts (than just the DS card). Very useful, keep track of sales with the app! (Apple, Swebus, Comviq, Tele2, Tre, SF Cinema, Adlibris, &amp;hellip;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooms</title>
      <link>/posts/rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rooms/</guid>
      <description>Rooms To find the location of rooms on campus you can go to Map (online/app) or download the Chalmers map app for smartphones.
Booking a room To book a room you need to create an event in the exchange calendar for that room.
Log in to the Outlook webmail client), go to the Calendar tab and click on new to create a new event.
Click on &amp;lsquo;Add a location or a room&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;Add room&amp;rsquo; and you will see which rooms are available at the chosen time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student-union/</guid>
      <description>The Student Union / Doctorand Students Guild (DS) As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right and the obligation to be part of the Chalmers Student Union. Sign up for the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecenat. You can use your Student Union card to buy discounted food at campus restaurants. The fee is 190 SEK every semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses, Exams &amp; Certificates</title>
      <link>/posts/courses-exams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/courses-exams/</guid>
      <description>A list of links to register/view exams and courses can be found at https://student.portal.chalmers.se/en/chalmersstudies/Pages/services.aspx.
Exam Registration / Check registered credits To be able to attend the exam for a course, you need to register for it. There&amp;rsquo;s more information on how to do that at https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/courses/subject-courses-for-phd-students/
Course Schedules, room info In Time-edit (https://cloud.timeedit.net/chalmers/web/) you can find information on when and where a course is given at Chalmers.
List of Passed Courses and Certificate Here you can get the list of credits for the courses you have completed once they are reported to the system by the examiner https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>/posts/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/library/</guid>
      <description>Access material when off-campus Add your publications to CLP Books You can request and access material such as books and articles you need for you research at the Library website You can request/recommand a (paper/online) book for library. (the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary need to be relevant to your research area).
Lending times:
Books : 1-3 weeks
E-book, articles: 1-3 days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/posts/union/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/union/</guid>
      <description>Union Sign up and start paying for Akademikernas a-kassa at least 12 months before graduation, so you can receive benefits if you have some months without income before your next employment starts.
Why</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/posts/xleftooverinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/xleftooverinfo/</guid>
      <description>Course directory  /chalmers/groups/edu2009/www/www.cse.chalmers.se/year/2015/course/TDA352_Cryptography accessable : http://www.cse.chalmers.se/edu/course/TDA352_Cryptography/ Simple sync script  Windows home directoory: file00.chalmers.se (accessable via smb://HOST or \\HOST)
Linux home directory sol.ita.chalmers.se (accessable via smb://HOST or \\HOST) More info
Calendar In Sweden knowing week numbers is really useful (Google calendar support showing week # in the calendar view). In Ubuntu to show calendar with week numbers (or set it in &amp;ldquo;time &amp;amp; calendar&amp;rdquo; indicator) :
gsettings set org.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>