<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Council Documents on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/council-documents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Council Documents on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/council-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD student Ombudsman Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD student Ombudsman (hereafter referred to as “the PhD ombudsman”) is an official role held by a PhD student, nominated and elected by the doctoral students at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and approved by the CSE department and/or the graduate school.
 The role of the PhD ombudsman is to help PhD students who experience difficulties during the course of their PhD, by providing counsel and acting as a neutral intermediary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity Plan</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</guid>
      <description>This activity plan outlines the items and issues which the council plans to work on during its term in 2019-2020. This is a high-level, strategic plan of activities.
PhD students Representation Background Representation of PhD students in various department committees, such as the department council or research education committee such as DS, SWEET, PhD Mingle, etc.
Action We plan to properly represent the PhD students in these different committees and report back the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD Student Council Last update: 2018-05-09
Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council (hereafter referred to as “the council”) is a group of representatives for the doctoral students at the combined Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) at Chalmers University of Technology and Gothenburg University (hereafter referred to as “the department”). The name of the council is “The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>