<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>At the start of your PhD on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/at-the-start-of-your-phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in At the start of your PhD on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/at-the-start-of-your-phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New in Sweden</title>
      <link>/posts/new-in-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-in-sweden/</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps</title>
      <link>/posts/first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-steps/</guid>
      <description>The first days when you start your PhD in an unknown place can be a bit disorienting or overwhelming, so here is a (possibly incomplete) checklist of things you should keep in mind for your first days around. (If you find out there&amp;rsquo;s information that should be included or updated, please send us a mail!)
Also, if you come from another country you should also read the New in Sweden page to get an idea of things you should take care of when you arrive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses Chalmers employees use the Primula portal to apply for vacation days and leave, report sick days, and apply to be compensated for travel expenses and other expenses.
You log in with your CID username and password.
There you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep your Personal Data page up-to-date (in particular if you move to a new address).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software/</guid>
      <description>Commercial Software Available Here you will find instructions to get programs such as several Affinity tools, Adobe tools, Matlab, Office, etc. https://it.portal.chalmers.se/itportal/GenAnst/SoftwareGeneral#anvisningar
If you need other software, talk with your supervisor or with Technical Support (you can find them at the bottom of this page)
Microsoft tools Microsoft On-The-Hub Some versions of Windows, MS Office Home/Professional, utitily software (antivirus), Parallels Desktop for Mac, and many others (The software offered might change).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email</title>
      <link>/posts/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/email/</guid>
      <description>Setting up your Chalmers email account IMAP  imap.chalmers.se - port: 993 username : CID Auth method: CID password Connection: SSL/TLS // Note : Thunderbird test doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.  SMTP  smtp.chalmers.se : 587 username : CID Auth method: NTLM (TLS also works) Connection: STARTTLS (if required)  iOS Detail setting from IT portal - Select Exchange account - On the first page, use &amp;lsquo;CID@chalmers.se&amp;rsquo; - Domain: NET - Server: webmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student-union/</guid>
      <description>The Student Union / Doctorand Students Guild (DS) As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right and the obligation to be part of the Chalmers Student Union. Sign up for the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecenat. You can use your Student Union card to buy discounted food at campus restaurants. The fee is 190 SEK every semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/posts/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/internet/</guid>
      <description>Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go toCDKS
Home directory of remote servers You have a limited (but large) space at Chalmers servers just for you! - enter in your Termial - type &amp;lsquo;ssh -X CID@remote12.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>