<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PhD Specifics on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/phd-specifics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PhD Specifics on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/phd-specifics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-Up Meetings</title>
      <link>/posts/follow-up-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/follow-up-meetings/</guid>
      <description>What are Follow-up Meetings? TODO
Scheduling You should have at least one follow-up meeting every year, the first one being about 6 months after you start working at Chalmers. If things happen that might prevent you from following the plan set in your most recent follow-up meeting, such as sick leave or parental leave, you should schedule a new meeting as soon as possible to discuss what changes are needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTS - Generic &amp; Transferable Skills</title>
      <link>/posts/gts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gts/</guid>
      <description>During your education you need to obtain several credits from GTS courses, some of which are mandatory.
List of GTS courses https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/working-at-chalmers/employee/role-related-development/development-for-phd-students/
List of mandatory and optional courses for Chalmers students https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/courses/courses-and-activities-within-gts/
List of mandatory courses for GU students https://medarbetarportalen.gu.se/internt-itufak/utbildning-pa-forskarniva/kurser/?languageId=100001&amp;amp;skipSSOCheck=true
More information on GTS courses gathered by the Doctoral Students Guild at Chalmers: https://www.notion.so/Generic-and-Transferable-Skills-GTS-a554319dc8554789b284e3339a688bd1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Licentiate Degree</title>
      <link>/posts/licenciate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/licenciate/</guid>
      <description>About halfway through your PhD studies at Chalmers you are required to defend your Licentiate thesis. This is a formal presentation with your examiner and an external opponent, where you should present the work you have done up to that moment.
The following document has information on how to prepare for the seminar. Note there&amp;rsquo;s specific guidelines for CSE, make sure to adhere to those too: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/licentiate/preparations-for-licentiate-seminars/
If you are a Chalmers student, to be eligible for the Licentiate degree you are required to have completed a series of credits, some of which need to be from specific GTS courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis LaTeX Template</title>
      <link>/posts/thesis-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thesis-template/</guid>
      <description>We at the council have a github repository with a LaTeX template for you to use for your Licentiate or PhD thesis.
You should double-check the requirements for your thesis and that the template matches them.
If the requirements have been updated, we would appreciate very much if you could send a pull-request to fix the template.
We will welcome any other improvements that you find it needs as pull-requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student-union/</guid>
      <description>The Student Union / Doctorand Students Guild (DS) As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right and the obligation to be part of the Chalmers Student Union. Sign up for the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecenat. You can use your Student Union card to buy discounted food at campus restaurants. The fee is 190 SEK every semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses, Exams &amp; Certificates</title>
      <link>/posts/courses-exams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/courses-exams/</guid>
      <description>A list of links to register/view exams and courses can be found at https://student.portal.chalmers.se/en/chalmersstudies/Pages/services.aspx.
Exam Registration / Check registered credits To be able to attend the exam for a course, you need to register for it. There&amp;rsquo;s more information on how to do that at https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/doctoral-studies-support/courses/subject-courses-for-phd-students/
Course Schedules, room info In Time-edit (https://cloud.timeedit.net/chalmers/web/) you can find information on when and where a course is given at Chalmers.
List of Passed Courses and Certificate Here you can get the list of credits for the courses you have completed once they are reported to the system by the examiner https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>