<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workplace on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/categories/workplace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workplace on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/workplace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps</title>
      <link>/posts/first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-steps/</guid>
      <description>The first days when you start your PhD in an unknown place can be a bit disorienting or overwhelming, so here is a (possibly incomplete) checklist of things you should keep in mind for your first days around. (If you find out there&amp;rsquo;s information that should be included or updated, please send us a mail!)
Also, we very much recommend, specially if you are coming from another country, that you also read the PhD Student Guide made by DS to get an idea of all the things you might need before you start working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organisational Structure</title>
      <link>/posts/organisational-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/organisational-structure/</guid>
      <description>These are the people that are in charge of you, in one way or another. You should find out who each one of them is.
 Supervisor: (possibly together with a co-supervisor) is the person who will overview your research, and who you should go to for any research-related issues. Examiner: Is the person who will act as your examiner during your PhD; they evaluate your progress and decide if a course you want to attend will count towards your PhD credits, so ask them about that before choosing to join a course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>Some useful links Unofficial PhD Student Guide by DS
Roles and Responsabilities
Intranet Here you might be able to find most of the information you might need about anything in the PhD. The drawbacks are there&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of information that might not be relevant to you so things are sometimes difficult to find. Requires login.
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Trips</title>
      <link>/posts/travelex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/travelex/</guid>
      <description>Chalmer&amp;rsquo;s Guidelines In the following link you can find the official guide from chalmers to book a trip: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/book-a-trip/
This link gives the basic guidelines for what expenses are covered and how you should pay for them and register them: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/expenses-travel-bill-and-entertainment/
Travel Approval Before you go: Find out cost estimate, check with your supervisor if your project can cover the cost. Fill in a BTA form (This form might be outdated, ask your division secretary just in case) (the form will be sent to your division head for signature and to your division secretary for reference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses Chalmers employees use the Primula portal to apply for vacation days and leave, report sick days, and apply to be compensated for travel expenses and other expenses.
You log in with your CID username and password.
There you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep your Personal Data page up-to-date (in particular if you move to a new address).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software &amp; Hardware</title>
      <link>/posts/software-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Internet Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go to CDKS
Email IMAP  imap.chalmers.se - port: 993 username : CID Auth method: CID password Connection: SSL/TLS // Note : Thunderbird test doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits (Discounts)</title>
      <link>/posts/benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benefits/</guid>
      <description>Health expense refund As a Chalmers employee you have the right to be refunded for up to 2000SEK/year for expenses related to health and wellness.
Find more information at the intranet https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/working-at-chalmers/working-environment-health/health/wellness/
Mecenat The Mecenat card from DS gives you access to more student discounts (than just the DS card). Very useful, keep track of sales with the app! (Apple, Swebus, Comviq, Tele2, Tre, SF Cinema, Adlibris, &amp;hellip;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooms</title>
      <link>/posts/rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rooms/</guid>
      <description>Rooms To find the location of rooms on campus you can go to Map (online/app) or download the Chalmers map app for smartphones.
Booking a room To book a room you need to create an event in the exchange calendar for that room.
Log in to the Outlook webmail client), go to the Calendar tab and click on new to create a new event.
Click on &amp;lsquo;Add a location or a room&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;Add room&amp;rsquo; and you will see which rooms are available at the chosen time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>/posts/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/library/</guid>
      <description>Access material when off-campus Add your publications to CLP Books You can request and access material such as books and articles you need for you research at the Library website You can request/recommand a (paper/online) book for library. (the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary need to be relevant to your research area).
Lending times:
Books : 1-3 weeks
E-book, articles: 1-3 days</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>