<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>document on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/tags/document/</link>
    <description>Recent content in document on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/document/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/ombudsman-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD student Ombudsman Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD student Ombudsman (hereafter referred to as “the PhD ombudsman”) is an official role held by a PhD student, nominated and elected by the doctoral students at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and approved by the CSE department and/or the graduate school.
 The role of the PhD ombudsman is to help PhD students who experience difficulties during the course of their PhD, by providing counsel and acting as a neutral intermediary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity Plan</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/activity-plan/</guid>
      <description>This activity plan outlines the items and issues which the council plans to work on during its term in 2019-2020. This is a high-level, strategic plan of activities.
PhD students Representation Background Representation of PhD students in various department committees, such as the department council or research education committee such as DS, SWEET, PhD Mingle, etc.
Action We plan to properly represent the PhD students in these different committees and report back the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps</title>
      <link>/posts/first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-steps/</guid>
      <description>The first days when you start your PhD in an unknown place can be a bit disorienting or overwhelming, so here is a (possibly incomplete) checklist of things you should keep in mind for your first days around. (If you find out there&amp;rsquo;s information that should be included or updated, please send us a mail!)
Also, if you come from another country you should also read the New in Sweden page to get an idea of things you should take care of when you arrive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Statutes</title>
      <link>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/council-docs/council-statutes/</guid>
      <description>Statutes of the Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) PhD Student Council Last update: 2018-05-09
Section 1: General principles  The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council (hereafter referred to as “the council”) is a group of representatives for the doctoral students at the combined Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) at Chalmers University of Technology and Gothenburg University (hereafter referred to as “the department”). The name of the council is “The Computer Science and Engineering PhD Student Council”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>Some useful links Handbook for doctoral studies Procedure for licentiate Thesis, followup meetings and needed forms
Doctoral Portal
Intranet
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)
Licentiate degree (There are rules specific to CSE, make sure to follow those in addition to the basic ones described in the same page)
Follow-up meetings
GTS courses
Insidan (old intranet, deprecated)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Trips</title>
      <link>/posts/travelex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/travelex/</guid>
      <description>Chalmer&amp;rsquo;s Guidelines In the following link you can find the official guide from chalmers to book a trip: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/book-a-trip/
This link gives the basic guidelines for what expenses are covered and how you should pay for them and register them: https://intranet.chalmers.se/en/tools-support/general-support-services/conferences-meetings-business-travel/business-travels/expenses-travel-bill-and-entertainment/
Travel Approval Before you go: Find out cost estimate, check with your supervisor if your project can cover the cost. Fill in a BTA form (This form might be outdated, ask your division secretary just in case) (the form will be sent to your division head for signature and to your division secretary for reference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses Chalmers employees use the Primula portal to apply for vacation days and leave, report sick days, and apply to be compensated for travel expenses and other expenses.
You log in with your CID username and password.
There you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep your Personal Data page up-to-date (in particular if you move to a new address).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software/</guid>
      <description>Commercial Software Available Here you will find instructions to get programs such as several Affinity tools, Adobe tools, Matlab, Office, etc. https://it.portal.chalmers.se/itportal/GenAnst/SoftwareGeneral#anvisningar
If you need other software, talk with your supervisor or with Technical Support (you can find them at the bottom of this page)
Microsoft tools Microsoft On-The-Hub Some versions of Windows, MS Office Home/Professional, utitily software (antivirus), Parallels Desktop for Mac, and many others (The software offered might change).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombudsman</title>
      <link>/posts/ombudsman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ombudsman/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a local PhD Ombudsman Nominee Deadline : TBD This is your chance to improve you fellow PhD student&amp;rsquo;s experience, by listening them and helping them to look at their problem from a different prospective.Despite there are several different contacts that are there to help you, such as the Doktorandombudet (DOMB), in agreement with the CSE Research School, we re-introduce the figure of the CSE PhD Ombudsman as an elected PhD student that has the role to locally listen and help other PhD students by giving an objective point of view on difficult and sometimes tedious PhD related problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buddy System</title>
      <link>/posts/buddysystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/buddysystem/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking to expand our buddy pool with buddies from all divisions! This is your chance to improve a new PhD student’s experience, by helping them figure out everything you wish you had known when you started here!
Do you have some wise advice or useful tips you wish someone had given you at the start of your PhD journey?
This could be anything from questions about navigating department bureaucracy, advice on apartment hunting in Gothenburg, tips on socializing in a new city/country, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits (Discounts)</title>
      <link>/posts/benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benefits/</guid>
      <description>Health expense refund As a Chalmers employee you have the right to be refunded for up to 2000SEK/year for expenses related to health and wellness. This can be done through a portal called Benify. There you can directly buy discounted gym memberships, book massages, etc, making use of your wellness refund. You can also send in receipts and be reimbursed, see below:
How to claim expenses and to get refunds  Go to insidan On the right-most column select Chalmers Plus in the menu under &amp;lsquo;E-tjanst&amp;rsquo;, clic visa Insert CID and CID-password Click on &amp;lsquo;wellness receipts&amp;rsquo; Follow instruction on how to register a receipt (useful instructions in english also under &amp;lsquo;How do I register my expenses?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email</title>
      <link>/posts/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/email/</guid>
      <description>Setting up your Chalmers email account IMAP  imap.chalmers.se - port: 993 username : CID Auth method: CID password Connection: SSL/TLS // Note : Thunderbird test doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.  SMTP  smtp.chalmers.se : 587 username : CID Auth method: NTLM (TLS also works) Connection: STARTTLS (if required)  iOS Detail setting from IT portal - Select Exchange account - On the first page, use &amp;lsquo;CID@chalmers.se&amp;rsquo; - Domain: NET - Server: webmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooms</title>
      <link>/posts/rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rooms/</guid>
      <description>Rooms To find the location of rooms on campus you can go to Map (online/app) or download the Chalmers map app for smartphones.
Booking a room To book a room you need to create an event in the exchange calendar for that room.
Log in to the Outlook webmail client), go to the Calendar tab and click on new to create a new event.
Click on &amp;lsquo;Add a location or a room&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;Add room&amp;rsquo; and you will see which rooms are available at the chosen time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student-union/</guid>
      <description>The Student Union / Doctorand Students Guild (DS) As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right and the obligation to be part of the Chalmers Student Union. Sign up for the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecenat. You can use your Student Union card to buy discounted food at campus restaurants. The fee is 190 SEK every semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses &amp; Certificates</title>
      <link>/posts/exams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/exams/</guid>
      <description>PhD-level Courses TODO: how to register and report credits for phd-level courses
Exam Registration / Check registered credits  go to the Doctoral Portal click on &amp;ldquo;Login&amp;rdquo; (written in blue in the greyish submenu bar on the top of the page) enter your cid + password click on: &amp;ldquo;Examination, sign-up/cancel sign up&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;Create transcript of records, postgraduate studies&amp;rdquo;  (important : make sure you are in the Doctoral Portal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/posts/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/internet/</guid>
      <description>Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go toCDKS
Home directory of remote servers You have a limited (but large) space at Chalmers servers just for you! - enter in your Termial - type &amp;lsquo;ssh -X CID@remote12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>/posts/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/library/</guid>
      <description>Access material when off-campus Add your publications to CLP Books You can request and access material such as books and articles you need for you research at the Library website You can request/recommand a (paper/online) book for library. (the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary need to be relevant to your research area).
Lending times:
Books : 1-3 weeks
E-book, articles: 1-3 days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printers</title>
      <link>/posts/print/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/print/</guid>
      <description>Printer Web interface to printers You can use web interface to see nearby printers, download drivers or directly send pdf, txt files to be printed.
Setup on linux with SMB (tested on Ubuntu 18.x, 16.x, 14.x, 12.x) See instructions here.
Setup on Windows Printing via ipp/kerberos: Copy krb5.conf in this repository to /etc/krb5.conf and run:
test -d $HOME/.cups || mkdir $HOME/.cups cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF &amp;gt;$HOME/.cups/client.conf ServerName print.chalmers.se GSSServiceName HTTP EOF  In older versions of CUPS, you may have to add those lines to the system-wide configuration file in /etc/cups/client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worker Union</title>
      <link>/posts/union/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/union/</guid>
      <description>Union Sign up and start paying for Akademikernas a-kassa at least 12 months before graduation, so you can receive benefits if you have some months without income before your next employment starts.
Why</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>