<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Document on CSE PhD council</title>
    <link>/tags/document/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Document on CSE PhD council</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 CSE PhD council</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/document/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits</title>
      <link>/posts/benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benefits/</guid>
      <description>Health expense refund As a Chalmers employee you have the right to be refunded for up to 2000SEK/year for expenses related to health and wellness. This can be done through a portal called Benify. There you can directly buy discounted gym memberships, book massages, etc, making use of your wellness refund. You can also send in receipts and be reimbursed, see below:
How to claim expenses and be refund - go to [insidan](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email and software</title>
      <link>/posts/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/email/</guid>
      <description>Setting up your Chalmers email account IMAP  imap.chalmers.se - port: 993 username : CID Auth method: CID password Connection: SSL/TLS // Note : Thunderbird test doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.  SMTP  smtp.chalmers.se : 587 username : CID Auth method: NTLM (TLS also works) Connection: STARTTLS (if required)  iOS Detail setting from IT portal - Select Exchange account - On the first page, use &amp;lsquo;CID@chalmers.se&amp;rsquo; - Domain: NET - Server: webmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooms</title>
      <link>/posts/rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rooms/</guid>
      <description>Rooms To find the location of rooms on campus you can go to Map (online/app) or download the Chalmers map app for smartphones.
Booking a room To book a room you need to create an event in the exchange calendar for that room.
Log in to the Outlook webmail client), go to the Calendar tab and click on new to create a new event.
Click on &amp;lsquo;Add a location or a room&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;Add room&amp;rsquo; and you will see which rooms are available at the chosen time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificates</title>
      <link>/posts/certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/certificates/</guid>
      <description>List of passed courses and certificate Having an official list of passed courses can be useful i.e. when applying for scholarship, and to submit your Licentiate / PhD defence request.
Student portal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exams</title>
      <link>/posts/exams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/exams/</guid>
      <description>Exam Registration / Check registered credits  go to the Doctoral Portal click on &amp;ldquo;Login&amp;rdquo; (written in blue in the greyish submenu bar on the top of the page) enter your cid + password click on: &amp;ldquo;Examination, sign-up/cancel sign up&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;Create transcript of records, postgraduate studies&amp;rdquo;  (important : make sure you are in the Doctoral Portal! If you end up in the Student Portal &amp;ldquo;your account doesn&amp;rsquo;t have permission to use the service&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/posts/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/internet/</guid>
      <description>Wireless access to eduroam There is an installer in eduroam website (even for Linux) that embedded the eduroam certificate.
Manual setup  Login ID: CID@chalmers.se Anonymous ID: empty Password: CID password Authentication: MSCHAPv2 EAP type: PEAP Eduroam certificate is in eduroam.pem  Change password for CID / NOMAD Go toCDKS
Home directory of remote servers You have a limited (but large) space at Chalmers servers just for you! - enter in your Termial - type &amp;lsquo;ssh -X CID@remote12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>/posts/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/library/</guid>
      <description>Access material when off-campus Add your publications to CLP Books You can request and access material such as books and articles you need for you research at the Library website You can request/recommand a (paper/online) book for library. (the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary need to be relevant to your research area).
Lending times:
Books : 1-3 weeks
E-book, articles: 1-3 days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing / Printers</title>
      <link>/posts/print/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/print/</guid>
      <description>Printer Web interface to printers You can use web interface to see nearby printers, download drivers or directly send pdf, txt files to be printed.
Setup on linux with SMB (tested on Ubuntu 18.x, 16.x, 14.x, 12.x) See instructions here.
Printing via ipp/kerberos: Copy krb5.conf in this repository to /etc/krb5.conf and run:
test -d $HOME/.cups || mkdir $HOME/.cups cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF &amp;gt;$HOME/.cups/client.conf ServerName print.chalmers.se GSSServiceName HTTP EOF  In older versions of CUPS, you may have to add those lines to the system-wide configuration file in /etc/cups/client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software/</guid>
      <description>Free commercial software Worth looking (OS and utitily software(antivirus) and domain specific softwares like MATLAB and &amp;hellip;) Windows share:
 smb://syros.ce.chalmers.se \\syros.ce.chalmers.se
 Domain: NET
 username: CID
  syros directory tree output of &amp;ldquo;tree -L 3 -d&amp;rdquo; on smb://syros.ce.chalmers.se/program/
Microsoft tools Different version of Windows (even ancient DOS), SQL server and visual studio and more. You need to specify your university (Chalmers).
Microsoft tools Almost everything except MS-Office which is accessable from SYROS server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling as a Chalmers&#39; Employee</title>
      <link>/posts/travelex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/travelex/</guid>
      <description>Travel Approval Before you go: Find out cost estimate, check with your supervisor if your project can cover the cost. Fill in a BTA form (the form will be sent to your division head for signature and to your division secretary for reference).
Book the travel using the Chalmers (or GU) travel agent (Lingmerths).
Travel: Enjoy it, pay with your Chalmers MasterCard or in other ways, just remember to keep receipts for any non-food expense (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Package</title>
      <link>/posts/intropackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intropackage/</guid>
      <description>Expense report and Vacation Primula [TODO] Procedure of filing expense report (including LRS)
How to select meal benefits  For each meal M on each day there are three options:  Checking box with meal benefits (B): choose this option if meal M is included as part of another fee (for example, a lunch that is included in a conference registration fee) and M is not a breakfast. Checking box without meal benefits (N): choose this optin if meal M is offered by a third party (for example, if you are a guest and your host pays for M) or M is a breakfast (which is usually included in hotel fee) Not checking either box (E): choose this option if you pay for meal M yourself (for example, you go out to a restaurant and pay your share of the bill out of your own pocket) (Don&amp;rsquo;t clicking on anything)   The consequences of these options are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primula</title>
      <link>/posts/primula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/primula/</guid>
      <description>Report vacations, leave, expenses Chalmers employees use the Primula portal to apply for vacation days and leave, report sick days, and apply to be compensated for travel expenses and other expenses.
You log in with your CID username and password.
Here you can also check how many vacation days you have left (or accumulated), your employment statements and records.
Do not forget to keep you Personal Data page up-to-date (in particular if you move to a new address).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union</title>
      <link>/posts/union/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/union/</guid>
      <description>Union Sign up and start paying for Akademikernas a-kassa at least 12 months before graduation, so you can receive benefits if you have some months without income before your next employment starts.
Why</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>/posts/linksuseful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linksuseful/</guid>
      <description>Some useful links Handbook for doctoral studies Procedure for licentiate Thesis, followup meetings and needed forms
Doctoral Portal
Insidan
Welcome leaflet with a bunch of useful organizational information (also for non-PhDs)
Licentiate degree
Follow-up meetings
GTS courses</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Union</title>
      <link>/posts/student_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/student_union/</guid>
      <description>Student union As a Chalmers PhD student you have the right (and the obligation) to be part of the Student Union. Sign up to the Student Union, this automatically gives you 3 months in the SGS queue and gives you access to all student discounts Mecent. The fee is 250 SEK fee every semester.
** Student union card is REQUIRED for taking an exam ** NOTE: If you are a Chalmers PhD student, in order to graduate you need to prove you have payed the fee to the Student Union for all the semesters you have work at Chalmers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>